好的，又一个迪拜视频。
Okay, so another Dubai video.
超级工程✓，造价200亿美元，嗯，差不多。
Mega projects check, 20 billion US dollars, yeah, seems about right.
好的，这次是什么呢？
Okay, so what's this then?
肯定是世界上最大的什么，也许是一座人工岛。
It's got to be the world's biggest something, maybe an island.
哦。
Oh.
一条下水道？
A sewer?
哦。哦。行吧。
Oh. Oh. Okay.
好吧，原来这个地球上最土豪的城市有一个管道问题，
Well, it turns out the blingiest city on Earth has a plumbing problem,
而且这个问题已经蔓延到了街头。
and it's one that is taking to the streets.
所以，为了不束手无策，这个奢华的酋长国正在豪掷千金
So, in an attempt to avoid being up a creek without a paddle,
上马一个超级工程——你不会在旅游宣传册封面上看到它，
the extravagant Emirates is splashing its cash on a mega project that you won't see on the cover of a tourism brochure,
而且你肯定也不会想把你的法拉利停在它旁边。
and one you definitely wouldn't want to park your Ferrari next to.
让我们回到千禧年初。
Let's take a trip back to the naughties.
谁还记得这个？
Who remembers this?
你看，所有的粪便车都排成了一列。
Here's all the poop trucks all lined up.
要花多少钱？
How much money?
每辆车1万加仑。
10,000 gallons each.
这就是名字起得很委婉的"迪拜粪便蛇"，
It's the flatteringly named Dubai poop snake,
是这座城市标志性成就背后那个不那么光鲜的代价。
and it's the rather less glamorous consequence of the city's crowning achievement.
2010年，迪拜凭借这座巨无霸地标的落成震撼登上世界舞台，
In 2010, Dubai burst onto the global stage with the completion of this mahoosive icon,
这是一项将技术实力与惊人野心融为一体的非凡成就。
an extraordinary accomplishment blending technical skill and breathtaking ambition.
迪拜就这样宣告崛起，
Dubai had arrived, baby,
而这座"泰坦尼克"级别的高塔开启了一个快速城市化的新时代——
and this Titanic tower ushered in a new era of rapid urban development,
专家们管这叫"多即是美，少即乏味"。
which experts refer to as more is more and less is snore.
但是，以这样的光速发展，自然有起有落——
But, growing at such light speed had its ups and downs,
准确地说，是地下的落。
underground to be precise.
据说这座巨塔当初并没有接入城市污水系统，
The legend goes that this vast tower wasn't connected to the city's sewage system,
而是需要源源不断的油罐车来运走它的呃……排泄物。
and instead needed a constant supply of tankers to carry away its uh waste.
这个说法并不完全准确，
That's not entirely correct,
但真相也好不到哪里去。
but the truth isn't much better.
事实上，哈利法塔是有接入管道的，
In reality, the Burj Khalifa was plumbed in,
但整个市中心的污水系统早已超负荷运转，
but the sewage system for the entire downtown core was already over capacity
在那里建造世界最高楼不过是压垮骆驼的最后一根稻草。
and building the world's tallest skyscraper there was just the cherry on top.
确实有数千辆污水罐车被调来处理这些"不受欢迎的货物"，
Thousands of sewage trucks were indeed called in
直到系统追上了需求。
to take receipts of these unwanted deliveries
until the system caught up.
如今，哈利法塔配备了一套精密的污水处理系统，
Today, the Burj Khalifa makes use of a sophisticated sewage treatment system
把处理后的水泵出，通过喷泉喷向地面，
that cleans that and pumps it back out through fountains
供所有人欣赏。
for the enjoyment of everyone at ground level.
但哈利法塔虽然自己"整顿"好了，
But while the Burj Khalifa might have cleaned up his act,
城市其余地方的问题却只增不减。
the problem for the rest of the city has only gotten worse.
朱美拉棕榈岛，这座城市另一个标志性超级工程，坐拥全球最顶级的房产，
The Palm Jumeirah, another of the city's iconic mega projects, might contain some of the most exclusive real estate in the world,
但它也未能幸免于迪拜令人头疼的臭味问题。
but it's not immune from Dubai's problematic pong.
2018年，有人发现未经处理的污水从岛屿东部新月形地带的路面上涌出。
In 2018, raw sewage was spotted flowing onto the road on the eastern crescent of the island.
源头是这里——一座超负荷运转的临时污水处理设施。
It had come from this, a temporary sewage treatment plant that was overloaded.
据一名目击者表示："
According to one eyewitness,
已经这样大约六个月了，臭死了。
"It's been like this for about 6 months and it smells.
污水一直积在路面上，甚至溅到了蓝色施工围板上。而且这不是个例。
Sewage has been lying on the road and is even splattered on the blue construction boards. And this wasn't
这不是偶发事件。
a one-off.
2019年，朱美拉棕榈岛的居民投诉管道问题持续存在——
In 2019, residents on the Palm Jumeirah complained of chronic issues with plumbing,
臭味难忍、污水管堵塞、家中供水中断。"
a persistent bad smell, blocked sewage pipes, and broken water supply to their homes."
但这座城市糟糕的管道系统带来的最戏剧性的冲击，发生在2024年。
But the most dramatic impact of the city's poor plumbing came in 2024.
阿联酋遭遇暴洪袭击，经历了有记录以来最强降雨。
The UAE was struck by flash floods after it suffered the heaviest rains since records began.
道路变成了河流。
Roads turned into rivers.
迪拜国际机场的跑道被洪水淹没。
The tarmac flooded at Dubai International Airport.
洪水压垮了城市的排水系统，
The floods overwhelmed the city's drainage system
整个酋长国各地均有报告称污水与洪水混合。
and there were reports across the Emirates of sewage mixing with flood water.
但如果你已经在想把兰博基尼换成橡皮艇，
But in case you're thinking of swapping your Lamborghini for a dinghy,
先别急——因为计划已经上马了。
then don't worry because a plan is a foot.
2023年，迪拜执行委员会批准建设迪拜战略污水隧道。
In 2023, the Executive Council of Dubai approved construction of the Dubai Strategic Sewage Tunnels.
这是一个宏大的计划，将赋予这座城市现代化、高度精密的污水系统，
A massive plan that's going to give this city a modern and sophisticated sewer system
让它在未来一个世纪都能保持"畅通"。
that'll keep it regular for the next century.
系统以两条深层隧道为核心，各自服务城市的不同区域。
It's designed around two deep-level tunnels, each one serving a different part of this city.
其中较大的一条将穿越50公里，贯穿最密集的人口区——
The larger of the two is going to run for 50 km through the most densely populated areas,
布尔迪拜、市中心和南部增长走廊。
Bur Dubai, Downtown, and the Southern Growth Corridor.
沿途，
Along the way,
污水通过10公里的支管网络呃……
waste is uh fed into the main tunnel
汇入主隧道。
through a 10 km network of link pipes.
隧道直径将随着流量增大，
The tunnel will gradually widen from 3.5 to 6.5 m over its length
沿线从3.5米逐渐扩宽至6.5米。
as its well, as its workflow is increased.
一旦污水进入隧道，
Once waste falls into the tunnel,
大自然的召唤就将由……大自然来协助完成。
the call of nature is going to be assisted by well, nature.
隧道以一定坡度建造，将逐渐下降90米深，
Built at an angle, the tunnel will gradually drop by a depth of 90 m,
借助重力推动一切向前流动。
allowing gravity to keep things moving.
最终，所有这些"货物"将汇聚到杰贝阿里的一座新泵站，
Eventually, everything is going to arrive here at a new pumping station in Jebel Ali,
在那里被提升最后几米，进入污水处理厂，
where the cargo is going to be lifted the final few meters into a sewage treatment plant
经过净化后重新利用。
before being cleaned and then reused.
系统的另一半服务于德伊勒区——
The second half of the system serves the Deira district,
这里有迪拜国际机场和城市众多著名的传统市集。
the area that houses Dubai International Airport and many of the city's famous souqs.
在这里，一条较短的25公里隧道将从棕榈德伊勒延伸至瓦尔桑的新设施。
Here, a shorter 25 km tunnel is going to run from Palm Deira to a new facility here at Al Warsan.
建设分为四个阶段。
Construction is split into four different phases.
第一批合同已于2025年与建筑公司签署，尚未公布官方完工日期，
The first contracts were signed with construction companies in 2025 and no official completion date's been set,
但预计将在2030年代初竣工。
but it's likely to be finished in the early 2030s.
估算造价218亿美元，
At an estimated 21.8 billion US dollars,
价格不菲，但这将给迪拜带来废物管理的黄金标准——
it won't come cheap, but it is going to give Dubai the gold standard of waste management,
污水界的劳斯莱斯，如果你愿意这么叫的话。
the Rolls-Royce of sewers, if you like.
我想知道我拥有一辆劳斯莱斯的概率有多大。
I wonder what the chances of me owning a Rolls-Royce is.
呃，没那么简单。
Nah, it's got more to it than that.
啊，简单！把随机一生收入折现至现值，减去固定支出，对虚拟增值和维护成本跑蒙特卡洛模拟，对盈余超出成本的结果积分——这就是我的概率。
Ah, easy. Model stochastic lifetime earnings discounted to present value minus fixed outgoing, run a Monte Carlo against phantom appreciation and maintenance, integrate the outcomes where surplus exceeds cost, and there is my probability.
你听懂了吗？
Did you follow that?
好吧，如果没有，那你需要今天的视频赞助商——Brilliant。
Well, if you didn't, then you need today's video sponsor, Brilliant.
这是一个很棒的学习平台，
It's a great learning platform
我一直在用它温习一些自己本该掌握的知识，
that I use all the time to brush up on stuff I really should know,
比如微积分，或者我感兴趣的其他学科，比如高等几何。
like calculus or other subjects I'm just curious about, like advanced geometry.
如果你跟我一样，
If you're anything like me,
你会喜欢挑战自己学点新东西的感觉，但一想到坐下来啃教科书就觉得无聊透顶。
you'll love the idea of challenging yourself to learn something new, but find the idea of sitting down with a textbook incredibly dull.
这正是Brilliant的用武之地。
That's exactly what Brilliant is built for.
它帮你以适合自己的方式学习。
It's there to help you learn in a way that suits you.
课程被拆分成小模块，
Courses are split up into small modules
你可以随时插空学，也可以一口气刷一整晚。
that you can dip in and out of or binge for a whole evening.
这门关于似然与概率的课程很棒，
This course on likeness and probability is great
它把一个直觉上感觉很简单的东西，用更严谨的方式帮你透彻理解。
because it takes something that feels intuitive and gives you a much more rigorous understanding of it.
从最基础的预测形式开始，不知不觉你就进入了复杂的复合概率领域。
It starts off with the most basic form of predictions, and before you know it, you're into really complex compound probabilities.
这让我想起来，
Which reminds me,
我应该已经买上我的劳斯莱斯了……不。
I should be getting my Rolls-Royce in No.
算了。不过不用担心我。
Never mind. Don't worry about me though.
点击下方链接或扫描屏幕上的二维码，
Check out the link below or scan the QR code on screen
免费试用Brilliant整整30天。
to try Brilliant for free for a full 30 days.
身为B1M的观众，你还能享受年度高级订阅8折优惠。
And as a viewer of the B1M, you can also get yourself 20% off an annual premium subscription.
我真心推荐，你们支持一下对我们也是大忙——
I really rate it and you'll be doing us a big favor as well,
虽然我不能保证你们能因此买到豪华跑车。
though I can't make you any promises about luxury supercars.
好，我们说到哪儿了？
Now, where were we?
哦，对了。
Oh, yeah.
下水道。
Sewers.
这个设计与伦敦的新超级污水隧道
The design is similar to London's new mega sewer,
有几分相似——后者于2025年正式投入使用。
which opened for business in 2025.
泰晤士潮道隧道从西向东
The Thames Tideway Tunnel runs for 25 km from west to east
延伸25公里，深入地下60米。
over 60 m beneath the city.
迪拜战略污水隧道建成后，
When the Dubai strategic sewage tunnels are complete,
将取代城市现有基础设施的大部分，
they'll replace much of the city's existing infrastructure
同时将污水处理能力提升700%，每天处理约2000万立方米的废水。
while increasing its wastewater capacity by 700% and managing some 20 million cubic meters of waste every day.
但如果这是个好主意，
But, if it's such a good idea,
为什么花了这么久？
then why is it taking so long?
现在的情况又是怎样？
And what's there at the minute?
嗯，首先，我们得倒回去一点。
Well, first, we've got to rewind a bit.
很难形容
It's hard to overstate
迪拜自2000年代初以来究竟
just how much Dubai has transformed
经历了多大的蜕变。
since the early 2000s.
哈利法塔只是迪拜一系列壮观工程中的最新一个——
The Burj Khalifa was just the latest
这些工程的目标是将这片
in a string of spectacles
昔日宁静的贸易港口
designed to transform this place
变成一个全球目的地，
from a sleepy trading post
最关键的是，
into a global destination
借此摆脱对石油的依赖。
and crucially in doing so,
win itself off its dependency on oil.
万一你还没get到这个消息——它成功了。
And in case you didn't get the memo, it worked.
从2008年起的短短11年间，迪拜人口翻了一番。
In just 11 years from 2008, Dubai's population doubled.
而在2003年至2023年的二十年间，>> >> 其经济规模翻了两番。
And in the period between 2003 and 2023, >> >> its economy quadrupled.
这个地方花费巨资添置各种奢靡之物，
Huge sums of money were spent on lavish baubles
成为了【清清嗓子】那个让人又爱又恨的浮华都市——
as this place became [clears throat] the glitzy, love-it-or-hate-it city
所有人今天都看得到。
that everyone can see today.
但是，当穿着品味可疑西装的房产中介们
But, as real estate agents in questionable suits
赚得盆满钵满时，
made their fortunes,
这座城市正在成为自身成功的受害者。
the city was becoming a victim of its own success.
电网不堪重负，停电变得司空见惯。
Power cuts became common as the grid struggled with demand.
为了容纳急速膨胀的人口而仓促修建的
As motorways were thrown up
高速公路，将街区彼此割断，
to accommodate the ballooning population,
活生生造出了一个城市规划师的噩梦。
neighborhoods became cut off, creating an urban planner's vision of hell.
当然，问题可不只是在地面上。
And of course, the problems weren't just above ground.
好，在
Now, before we go any further
我们继续今天的视频之前，
with today's video,
我需要暂停一下，
we need to stop everything
因为我有一个非常重大的消息，终于可以分享了。
because I have got some very big news
that I am finally allowed to share.
去年，
Last year,
企鹅兰登书屋问我
Penguin Random House asked me
愿不愿意写一本书。
if I'd like to write a book.
我说："愿意。"我写了这本书。
I said, "Yes." I've written the book.
就是这本。书名叫《Megabuilds》：
And here it is. It is called Megabuilds:
《将改变我们世界的十大巨型建筑工程》。在过去十年里，
10 Colossal Construction Projects That Will Change Our World. Over the last 10 years,
我有幸近距离目睹了这个星球上最令人叹为观止的建筑工程，它们全都在这里面。
I have had a front row seat on this planet's most incredible construction projects, and they are all in here.
我把它们都写了下来。
I've written about them.
我挖掘的深度超过了
I've gone deeper than I've ever gone before
以往任何视频、故事或长篇纪录片。
in any video, story, or any kind of like long-form documentary.
这是幕后故事，是近距离接触，
This is behind the scenes. It's up close and personal.
是与团队的相遇。
It meets the teams.
是人与人之间的故事，是工程的细节。
It's the human stories. It's the engineering in detail.
是我的亲身经历，以及在近距离接触这些工程的过程中遭遇的种种狼狈。
It's my personal experiences and some of the calamities I've had along the way getting up close with these projects.
我真的很享受写作这本书的过程。
I have really enjoyed writing this.
我有些朋友说："哦，不错。谁、谁帮你代笔的？"没人。我请不起什么花哨的代笔作者。
Some of my mates have been like, "Oh, nice. Who Who ghostwrote that for you?" No one. I can't afford a fancy ghostwriter.
是我。
Me.
是我写的。
I wrote this.
这本书里的每一个字，
Every single word of this has come from my head
都是从我脑子里流向我的笔记本电脑，
into my laptop and then into this book
再流进这本书的——都是为了你们的阅读乐趣。
all for your reading pleasure.
伙计们，我从没想过自己能写出一本书，但我写出来了，
Guys, I never thought I could write a book,
虽然我明显有偏见，
but I have
但我真的觉得它挺不错的。
and obviously I'm biased,
but I actually kind of think it's quite good.
现在已经开放预购了。链接在下方。
It is available to pre-order now. The link is below.
预购非常重要。
Pre-ordering is incredibly important.
基本上，我未来的幸福全靠你们预购这本书了。
Basically, my entire future happiness depends on you pre-ordering this book.
所以伙计们，如果你喜欢B1M，
So guys, if you love the B1M,
如果你喜欢这些故事，
if you love these stories,
如果你喜欢用通俗易懂、任何人都能读懂的方式
if you love learning more about construction in a down-to-earth way
深入了解建筑，
that's easy to understand and could be read by anyone,
那就去预购我的书《Megabuilds》吧。
go and pre-order my book Megabuilds today.
这并不是说迪拜完全没有管道。
It wasn't that there was a total lack of plumbing.
只是没有一个完整的系统。
There was just no coherent system.
到2000年代中期，迪拜已拥有逾1200公里的污水管道，
By the mid-noughties, Dubai had over 1,200 km of sewer pipes,
但这些管道都各自独立，
but those pipes all existed in small localized networks
分散在小型局部网络中，
that had been built ad hoc
是临时搭建的，而非统一规划的产物。
rather than in response to a citywide strategy.
还有另一个原因导致一切都举步维艰。
There was also another reason why everything was struggling.
他们没有利用重力让污水自然流向处理设施，
Instead of using gravity to wash the effluent downhill for treatment,
而是依靠一个拥有超过150座泵站的网络
they relied on a network of over 150 pumping stations
来维持污水流动。
to keep waste flowing through the pipes.
这是一种极其低效的运营方式，需要消耗大量能源。
It's a massively inefficient way to run the system requiring huge amounts of energy to operate.
如今，城市30%的碳排放来自为维持这些泵站运转所需的电力。
Today, 30% of the city's carbon emissions come from the power needed to keep these stations running.
但更重要的是，它们需要持续维护。
But more importantly, they require constant maintenance.
就像朱美拉棕榈岛的居民发现的那样，
As residents of the Palm Jumeirah discovered,
一旦某个泵站出故障，
as soon as one malfunctions,
后果会来得相当迅速。
the consequences make themselves known pretty quickly.
当系统应接不暇时，油罐车经常被叫来填补缺口。
As the system struggled to cope, tankers were often called upon to fill the gap when it was caught short.
2013年，运抵杰贝阿里这座处理厂的废物中，
In 2013, 30% of all the waste arriving at this plant
有30%是通过公路运送的。
in Jebel Ali was delivered by road.
粪便蛇回来了。
The poop snake was back.
排队情况极其糟糕，
Cues were so bad
司机们有时要等待长达24小时
that drivers were sometimes left waiting up to 24 hours
才能卸货，
to deposit their load,
而另一些人则自行其是。
while others took matters into their own hands.
最初几分钟有些紧张，但他们告诉我们，私自倾倒已是家常便饭。
After an initial nervous few minutes, they told us that dumping is routine.
那个年代，如果你有幸
In those days, if you were lucky enough
住在迪拜的海滨酒店，
to stay in one of Dubai's seafront hotels,
你可能真的就"出不了门"了。
you might literally have had to stay there.
油罐车
The overflow caused by tankers
私自倾倒废物
dumping waste
造成污水涌上海岸，海滩因此被迫关闭。
caused beaches to be closed as sewage clogged up on the shoreline.
好，说实话，这些挺恶心的。
Now, granted, this is all pretty gross.
但如果你觉得我们在不公平地
But in case you think we're being unfair
批评迪拜，
here, I want to reassure you
我想向你保证，我并不是在蓄意嘲讽这座城市。
that I'm not just trying to dunk on Dubai.
这并不是一个城市太热衷于面子工程、
This isn't a story of a city
忽视基础设施建设的故事。
that was too busy lavishing money on vanity projects
to get the basics of its infrastructure right.
千禧年中期至今的
That period of growth from the mid-noughties
这段增长期，
up to today was faster and more dramatic
比任何人预测的都要快速、剧烈。
than anyone could have predicted.
当你根本不知道未来五年会是什么样子，
And how can you plan and build a sophisticated infrastructure network
你怎么去规划和建设一个完善的基础设施网络？
when you don't know
what the next 5 years is going to look like?
>> >> 还记得我们之前提到的
>> >> Remember the Tideway Tunnel we mentioned earlier?
潮道隧道吗？
That's designed as an overflow system to supplement
那是作为溢流系统，用来补充伦敦那古老的维多利亚时代污水网络——
London's venerable Victorian sewage network,
那个网络早在1865年就开始运作了。
which opened all the way back in 1865.
1850年代的伦敦，
In the 1850s, London
与今天的迪拜处境相似。
was in a similar position
它经历着惊人的人口增长，
to Dubai now.
而它的废物处理系统——
It was experiencing extraordinary population growth,
也就是泰晤士河——已经不堪重负。
and its waste disposal system, aka the River Thames, was struggling to keep up.
事实上，正是1858年一个格外炎热干燥的
In fact, it took a particularly hot and dry summer
夏天——史称"大恶臭"——
in 1858, known as the Great Stink,
才终于逼得政府采取了行动。
for the government to finally act.
整座城市被一股恶臭笼罩，
The city was engulfed such a foul stench
国会大厦的窗帘都被浸泡在氯化石灰水中，
that the curtains in Parliament were soaked with lime chloride
试图掩盖那股气味。
to try and hide the smell.
约瑟夫·巴扎尔盖特在随后六年中建造的污水系统
The sewer built over the next 6 years by Joseph Bazalgette
被誉为市政工程的奇迹，
was hailed as a marvel of civic engineering,
但更重要的是，它标志着这座城市发展的一个转折点。
but more importantly, it signaled a turning point in the city's evolution.
迪拜要修的不只是污水系统。
It's not just the sewer Dubai is fixing up.
早在2021年，
Back in 2021,
迪拜统治者穆罕默德·本·拉希德·阿勒马克图姆酋长
the city's ruler, Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum,
就发布了《迪拜2040》——
unveiled Dubai 2040,
一项从根本上重塑这座城市的宏大计划，
a huge plan to fundamentally rewire the city
要将这里从一个停满布加迪的工地，
and transform it from a builder's yard with Bugattis
变成一个现代化的规划都市。
into a modern planned metropolis.
那些被高速公路围困的孤立街区，
Those isolated pockets hemmed in by motorways
将让位于五个新城市中心，
are going to give way to five new city centers,
所有居民日常所需的设施都在步行可达的范围内。
all with the amenities that residents need within short walking distances.
三个现有区域将被改造成小型城市中心，另外两个将从零开始新建。
Three existing areas are being redeveloped into mini city centers, and two new ones are being built from scratch.
6.8亿美元
680 million US dollars
将用于打造
is being spent on 8 million square meters
800万平方米供行人和骑行者使用的绿色廊道，
of green corridors for pedestrians and cyclists,
一个全新的地铁系统
and a new metro system
将让城市一半的区域都在距离地铁站800米的范围内，
is going to put half the city within 800 meters of a station,
使公共交通成为真正可行的出行方式。
making public transport a viable way to get around.
迪拜的战略污水隧道可能不是最光鲜、
Dubai's strategic sewer tunnels may not be the most
名字最好听的超级建筑工程，
glamorous or even most excitingly named of construction mega projects,
但它们极其重要。
but they are incredibly important.
这座城市以地面上的建筑
This city is world-famous for what it's built above the ground,
闻名于世，
but as is so often it's what's happening under the ground on projects that are out of sight, out of mind,
但往往正是那些埋在地下、不为人见、
由默默无闻的英雄们推动的工程，才让我们眼中的地面景观成为可能。
and led often by unsung heroes that makes what we see above ground happen.
今天的视频由Brilliant赞助。
Today's video was sponsored by Brilliant.
别忘了，你们
Don't forget that you guys can learn for free on Brilliant
可以点击brilliant.org/theB1M、扫描屏幕上的二维码或点击简介中的链接，
for a full 30 days by going to brilliant.org/theB1M,
免费使用Brilliant整整30天。
scanning the QR code on screen, or clicking the link in the description.
Brilliant还为我们的观众
Brilliant is also giving our viewers
提供年度高级订阅8折优惠，
20% off an annual premium subscription,
这意味着你将无限畅享Brilliant上的所有内容。
which means you'll get unlimited daily access to everything on Brilliant.
还有，老规矩，
And as always guys,
如果你喜欢这个视频，
if you enjoyed this video
想要更多来自这个建筑领域权威视频频道的内容，
and you want to get more from the definitive video channel for construction,
请按下那个冲水按钮。
push that flush button.
我是说，点击订阅按钮。
I mean, hit that subscribe button.